Center for Residence Life Rochester Institute of Technology Rochester, NY 14623-5603

Date: May 8, 2013

Subject: Application for Graduate Assistantship for Community Advocate

# Dear Daniel R Greer,

I am writing to express my interest to work as Graduate Assistant for Community Advocate in RIT. I completed my BSc. in Environmental Science in October 2012. My final year major project was on "Soil Properties and Carbon Stock under different land use in the mid hills of central Nepal" under supervision of Prof., Dr. Roshan Man Bajracharya. I have also worked as both Student representative and volunteer, as part of outreach program of high school, in Missionaries of Charity.

Although I am a recent college graduate, my maturity, academic background, potential, practical experience, and eagerness will make me a competent candidate for graduate assistant. Besides, GA is important for me to support my family to finance my studies as I'm very keen to enroll in MS in Environmental Science program in RIT.

I shall be looking forward for your positive response. Thank you for your time and consideration.

Thanking you,

Sincerely Yours Sumitra KC University ID: 83700-1445

# KC, SUMITRA

Pattipa – 4, Lalitpur, Nepal

Telephone: +977 1 5549621; Mobile: +977 9841611580

Email: sumitrakc17@gmail.com

#### PERSONAL STRENGTH

- Enthusiastic, knowledge hungry and self starter with a positive attitude.
- Enthusiastic about learning new science & technologies and enhancing current expertise.

#### **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Science; Major: Environmental Science, August 2008 – October 2012

Kathmandu University (KU), Dhulikhel, Kavre

Cumulative GPA: 3.84 (on 4.00 scale)

Intermediate of Science; Major: Biology with extra Mathematics,, July 2005 – May 2007

St. Xavier's College, Maitighar (affiliated to Tribhuvan University, Nepal),

Percentage: 74.29%

School Leaving Certificate (SLC), completed in 2005

Arniko Secondary Boarding School, Khumaltar, Lalitpur

Percentage: 82 %

#### **WORK EXPERIENCES AND ACTIVITIES**

### Internship

International Centre For Integrated Mountain Development (ICIMOD) (April 2013- Present)

# **Undergraduate Final Year Project**

Soil Properties and Carbon Stock under different land uses in the mid hills of central Nepal

Kathmandu University, 2012

#### **Team Member**

IEE Monitoring Of Environmental Impacts due to sand and gravel extraction in Banke District

Ministry of Local Development ,Government Of Nepal and Department of Environmental Science and Engineering, Kathmandu University, 2012

# Organizing Member;

Seminar entitled Climate Change and Sustainable Use of Resources in Nepal

Kathmandu University (22<sup>nd</sup> April- 23<sup>rd</sup> April, 2010)

#### Co-editor

Nature and Social Concern Society, Kathmandu University, 2009-2010

#### Social Work

Missionaries of Charity; (2005-2006)

Student Representative of Outreach Program, St. Xavier's College; (2005-2006)

Participant, Environment and Technology (SET) Exhibition; (February 2006)

Earthquake Liquefaction, St. Xavier's College

# Participant & First Runner-Up, Environment and Technology (SET) Exhibition; (February 2007)

Irrigation, St. Xavier's College

#### **General Member**

Kathmandu University Youth Red Cross Circle;2008

#### **General Member**

Friends of Zoo (FOZ), Central Zoo, Kathmandu; 1999-2001

# **TRAINING**

# **HTML** and JavaScript

Computer Assisted Learning, Kathmandu; completed on March 2003

#### **REFERENCES**

Professor, Dr. Roshan Man Bajracharya,

rmbaj@ku.edu.np

Professor ,Dr. Subodh Sharma

subodh.sharma@ku.edu.np

Dr. Rijan Bhakta Kayastha

rijan@ku.edu.np